# Kathirmalan Shanmugam

Full stack developer

in in/kathirmalan kathirmalan@gmail.com +33 7 54 47 43 89

"A Full-stack Software developer with 4+ years of industrial experience in web application development, hosting and maintaining the codebase. Expertise in client requirement analysis and delivered projects with significant optimizations."

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Backend Developper** | Ligne Bleue Cyber

July 2021 - present | Paris, FR

- Developed REST API service for Angular App
- Built several module service for the business model
- Developped React app for Totem device
- Responsible for reviewing and maintaing the code base

# Product Developer Intern | Hello Pomelo

Nov 2019 - Jun 2020 | Paris, FR

- Developed WebService API for IBM Watson chatbot using NLP
- Steered and developed the complete website for hellopomelo.com
- Built a Figma API tool using Python to create a task sheet that reduces the project manager's 95% manual effort.

# **Software Engineer** | Altspace Technologies

Feb 2017 - Jul 2018 | Chennai, IND

- Headed and developed the entire product Buddzie Books: a complete ERP Tool
- Leading the requirement gathering meetings with the business stakeholders and conducted feasibility analysis.
- Steered the complete migration project from Zoho suite to dedicated server
- Improved performance up to 90% for an application "Buddzie Recruit"

# Web Developer | Ecphasis Infotech

FEB 2016 - FEB 2017 | Chennai, IND

- Led the requirement gathering meetings with the client and complete the Feasibility Study.
- Led the Sprint Meetings
- Developed a complete event management tool from scratch and involved in the backend development using PHP
- Worked on Push Notifications features for Android Application using Google cloud messaging(GCM)

#### **SKILLS**

- PHP Javascript Python
- MySQL REST API Flask
- Symfony Bootstrap
- React js Codeigniter
- Version control

## **EXPERTISE**

- Web development
- · Logic problem solving
- Optimization of work flow
- · Process Automation

## **EDUCATION**

MSc in Data Science and Analytics

EPITA - Sep 2018 - Jul 2020 | Paris, FR

BE CSE, KGISL institute of Technology July 2011 - MAy 2015 | 4 YRS | IND

#### **CERTIFICATION**

- Oracle Database 10G: Introduction to SQL (2012)
- Oracle Database 10G: Program with PL/SQL (2012)
- REST APIs with Python
- React JS full-stack website development

### **INTERESTS**

Python Development Web3 | Blockchain IOS App Development

## Languages

English | French | Tamil